On this day in Xianyang
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）この日 咸陽(かんよう)では―
秦国(しんこく)の未来を左右する丞相(じょうしょう)の
任命式が行われていた
is the swearing-in ceremony of people that will have a major effect on the future of the State of Qin, the chancellors.
In the earlier political disturbance, Lü Buwei took the position of Prime Minister, the highest cabinet minister position.
呂不韋(りょふい)は先の政変で
大臣の最高職 相国(しょうこく)に就いたが
But in order to take hold of that position,
その地位を
確固たるものとするためには―
国事の決定に
直接 関わる右丞相と左丞相
the two positions of Right Chancellor and Left Chancellor became up for grabs.
２つの官位を
手中に収める必要があった
But...
しかし…
Lord Cai Ze...
（李斯(りし)）蔡沢(さいたく)どの
あの老人たちは何者ですか？
Who are those two elderly men?
（蔡沢）うむ… 弟君の手の者よ
The younger brother's subordinates...
For them to come forward like this is...
（蔡沢）彼らが表に出てくるとは…
W-Without further ado, we will make the announcement.
（台の老人）
そ… それでは これより発表する
First, we appoint Chanpingjun as Right Chancellor!
まずは 昌平君(しょうへいくん)を右丞相に任命する
（蔡沢）ヒョッ…
And next, the Left Chancellor...
次に左丞相…
We appoint Changwenjun as Left Chancellor!
昌文君(しょうぶんくん)を
左丞相に任命するものとする！
My lord!
（壁(へき)）殿ーっ！
（成蟜(せいきょう)）フッ…
クッ…
（蔡沢）こらえよ 李斯
Restrain yourself, Li Si.
Your era is sure to come someday.
お前の時代は必ず来る
（李斯）分かっております
I know...
This result was somewhat expected.
（昌平君）
この結果 ある程度は予想していた
But the younger brother really held this much power?
しかし 弟君が
これほどの力を持っていたとは…
Everyone that was released with me that day was part of the royal family.
あの夜
俺と共に解放されたのは全て王族
And each and every one of them were influential people with hidden connections.
しかも ひとりひとりが
闇の人脈を持つ有力者集団だ
If you were having problems like this, then you should've released us sooner, Ying Zheng.
こんなことなら―
もっと早く 俺たちを
解放しておくんだったな 嬴政(えいせい)
Should I breathe a sigh of relief here?
（昌文君）
これで良かったのだろうか？
By bringing in Chengjiao we can now fight on-par with Lü Buwei's camp,
成蟜を取り込んだことで―
我ら陣営は 呂不韋と
互角に渡り合えるまでになったが…
but looking at it from another angle, one could say that Chengjiao has gained power.
別の見方をすれば
成蟜が力をつけたとも取れる
“毒をもって毒を制す”というが
They say set a thief to catch a thief... but poison is poison.
やはり毒は毒…
（呂不韋）
ハハハハッ！ やりましたな 大王
Well done, my king.
しかし
かつての敵と手を組んでは―
But joining hands with your former enemy like this...
そこで死んだ犠牲者たちは
浮かばれぬでしょうな
the people that died in that battle may be turning in their graves.
To fall apart midway down our path would make them turn even more.
（政）道が途中で
ついえるほうが浮かばれぬ
Path?
道？
Well, I only have the poison of the harem.
まあ しかし
こちらは後宮という毒をのみ
そちらは 弟君という毒をのんだ
While you have swallowed the poison that is your younger brother.
So I suppose the victor will be
the one with the stronger poison?
さてさて 勝負の分かれ目は―
どちらの毒が
強かったかというところですかな？
（政）それも違う
（呂不韋）うん？
That is also wrong.
The strength of the poison does not matter.
毒の強弱など関係ない
What will be the determining factor in our duel
勝負の分かれ目は
結局 俺とお前の どっちが強いかだ
is whether you or I are stronger!
But of course, that is me.
（政）無論 俺だがな
You rotten young king...
若王(じゃくおう)め…
You've truly gotten bigger, haven't you?
誠に でかくなってきおったな
A New Legend
A few days later, Xin and the rest of the Feixin Unit arrived at the State of Qin's Eastern base camp, Dongjin Castle.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
それから数日後 信(しん)たち飛信(ひしん)隊は
秦国東の前線基地 東金城(とうきんじょう)に
到着した
Reorganization for units stationed nearby the national borders was occurring at Dongjin Castle,
東金城には
国境付近での再編成のため―
so the Yufeng Unit, Yuehua Unit, and other units had already gathered there.
既に 玉鳳(ぎょくほう)隊 楽華(がくか)隊ほか
各部隊が集結していたのである
We've finally made it.
（楚水(そすい)）やっと着きましたな
（信）予定より遅れた
Way later than expected.
Well quite a bit happened to us.
（楚水）
いろいろ ありましたからね
Yeah.
Here at Dongjin Castle,
そして 飛信隊は
国境での守備戦で失った人員を―
the Feixin Unit was supposed to replenish the men they lost on the defensive line of the national border.
ここ東金で
補充する手はずになっていた
I'm the captain of the Feixin Unit, Xin!
俺が飛信隊隊長 信だ！
I'm planning on giving some long, drawn out speech!
グダグダ長(なげ)え話をするつもりはない
古参も新参も よく聞け！
So all veterans and newcomers, listen up!
We, the Feixin Unit, have just one job!
俺たち飛信隊が やることは
ただひとつ！
To crush the enemy in front of us!
目の前の敵をぶっつぶす！
ただ それだけだ！
Now that a big war has ended, it feels like we can take a break for a while,
今は 大きな戦が終わって
一段落って感じだが
強(つえ)え敵は まだいる！
but there are still strong enemies out there!
So we're going to beat the shit out of them
だが 俺たちは
そいつらを ぶっつぶしていって
and make the name of the Feixin Unit echo throughout all of China!
飛信隊の名を
中華全土に響き渡らせる！
Don't fucking forget that!
このことを決して忘れるな！
いいか！
Got it?!
They're different...
（渕(えん)）違う…
臨時千人将となったときの檄(げき)とは
The resolve in his pep talks are different from when he was just a temporary Thousand-Man General!
今は覚悟が違うのだ！
（尾平(びへい)）ウウッ…
（去亥(きょがい)）うん？ 尾平 どうした？
Wei Ping, what's wrong?
It's just, seeing Xin up there like that...
だ… だってよ
さっきの信の姿見たら もう…
In the few years since the war against Wei under Duke Biao,
麃公(ひょうこう)将軍のもとで
戦った魏国(ぎこく)の戦から―
数年で千人隊の隊長だぜ
しかも 堂々としたもんだ
he's become a Thousand-Man General.
And a really great one!
As his senior from Chenghu Village, I can't help but cry.
城戸村(じょうとむら)の先輩としちゃ
泣けてくるのが当たり前じゃねえか
（昂(こう)）でも 随分
差がついちゃいましたね 尾平さん
But a huge gap's really grown between the two of you, hasn't it, Mr. Wei Ping?
ああ？ 昂 てめえ…
Ang, you bastard... You're a friggin' foot soldier!
平隊員のくせに！
（昂）ウワッ！
Ah, I'm sorry!
アアッ… ごめんなさい！
（尾平）待て 昂！
Hold it, Ang!
（田有(でんゆう)）あのころの顔ぶれも
だいぶ減ってしまったな
We've lost a lot of the people we had back then, too, haven't we?
Xie Ci, Shan Huo, Fa Jian, You Yi...
（松左(しょうさ)）
脇次(きょうじ) 山和(さんか) 茷建(ばっけん) 有義(ゆうぎ) 文穴(ぶんけつ) 邦(ほう)…
Wen Xue, Bang, and Wei Dao.
そして 尾到(びとう)
（沛浪(はいろう)）そうだな
Yeah, that's true...
I wish they could see the Feixin Unit now.
（崇原(すうげん)）あいつらにも
今の飛信隊を見せてやりたかった
We did a good job surviving this long.
（澤圭(たくけい)）
私たち よく生き残ったものです
I don't want to get sentimental, but I don't want to lose anyone else.
感傷的になるわけじゃないですが
もう １人も失いたくないですね
Mr. Ze, that's really not realistic.
（去亥）
澤さん それはムリって相談だ
（澤圭）
分かってます 戦ですからね
I know.
It's war, after all.
War... Where there are survivors, there are also those that leave.
戦か…
そこに残るヤツもいれば
出ていく者もいる
You mean Vice Captain Qiang Lei?
羌瘣(きょうかい)副長のことか？
I'm pretty sure... I heard she was heading for the State of Zhao.
確か 趙国(ちょうこく)に向かったって話だよな
Xin! You did it!
（男の子）信(しん) やったな！
That's one awesome enormous giant water bug, Xin!
（男の子１）
すげえ でけえタガメだな 信！
Yeah. You can make medicine out of this.
（信）ああ これ 薬になるんだ
母ちゃん 喜ぶぞ！
Mom'll be happy!
（男の子２）
信 俺にも触らせてくれよ
Xin, let me touch it!
No way! Catch your own!
ダメだ！ てめえで捕まえな
Cheapskate!
チェッ… ケチ！ 信のケチ！
You're so mean, Xin!
（信）なんだと この野郎 おい！
What'd you say, bastard?!
You're a cheapskate!
（男の子２）何すんだよ！
Ow ow ow!
（信）
いってえ！ いてて！ いってえ…
The giant water bug!
（男の子２）あっ タガメ！
（信）いってえよ！
It hurts! Hurry, somebody get it off!
誰か早く取ってくれ おい！
Hey!
Somebody, ow...
誰か！ 痛(いて)えってば 痛え…
（笑い声）
Comrades, huh?
（羌瘣）仲間か…
I know, Lusui.
分かっているよ 緑穂(りょくすい)
Right now, I must find You Lian and avenge Big Sis Xiang.
今は 象(しょう)姉の敵(かたき) 幽連(ゆうれん)を捜し出す
Hey there, Xin.
（蒙恬(もうてん)）よう 信！
Hey, Tian. You made it, huh?
よう 蒙恬 着いてたのか
（蒙恬）フフッ… 聞いていたよ
I heard.
千人将らしくはないが
信らしい いい檄だった
That pep-talk wasn't very much like the kind a Thousand-Man General would give, but it sounded very much like you.
うるせえ からかうな！
Sheddep. Quit makin' fun of me.
I'm not making fun, I'm serious!
からかってない　本心さ
So, that's a compliment then?
それ 褒めてんだろうな？
Of course.
当たり前だ
（信）だったら いい
Okay, then.
Come with me for a minute, Xin.
ちょっと つきあってくれ 信
What is it? I've got a lot to do.
何だよ？
いろいろと忙しいんだよ 俺は
It won't take long.
（蒙恬）すぐに終わるよ
Okay, fine, geez.
（信）…たく しゃあねえな！
Meanwhile at Xiangyang
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）そのころ 咸陽では―
信たちにとって
更に喜ばしい出来事が―
something else that gave Xin and the others reason to celebrate became apparent.
明らかになった
H-How could you, Xiang!
（陽(よう)）ひ… ひどいよ 向(こう)ちゃん！
そんなこと 全然…
You didn't tell me anything about...
B-But...
（向）だって…
So, did you talk to his majesty about it?
（陽）…で 大王さまには
ちゃんと お話ししたの？
Y-Yes...
（向）うん
（陽）…で？
And?
Xiang.
向…
（向）は… はい！
Yes?!
What's wrong?
どうした？
何か言いたいことでも あるのか？
Do you have something you want to tell me?
Can I speak freely?
よろしいでしょうか？
（政）かまわぬ
I don't mind.
（向）では 申し上げます
Well then, I'll say it...
The truth is...
実は…
I can't hear you.
聞こえぬ　もう少し大きい声で話せ
Please say it a bit louder.
Your majesty, I have... your child inside of me!
私に… 大王さまの子が！
ヒイッ…
申し訳ありません 大王さま
I'm terribly sorry, your majesty.
わ… 私
どうすればいいのでしょう？
I don't know what to do.
Is that what it was, Xiang?
（政）そうだったのか 向
えっ？
（政）そうか…
I see...
We have something we have to protect.
守るものが できたな
Your majesty...
大王さま…
（泣き声）
I'm really glad...
（陽）本当に良かった…
I'm so happy for you, Xiang. Congratulations! Congratulations!
良かったね 向ちゃん
おめでとう… おめでとう！
Yang...
陽ちゃん…
Thank you!
ありがとう 陽ちゃん！
（陽）向ちゃん！
（泣き声）
Xiang! Xiang!
Congratulations, my king!
おめでとうございます 大王さま
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
Yes, thank you.
ああ… ありがとう
Congratulations, your majesty.
おめでとうございます 大王さま
Now the foundation of the State of Qin is building into a prosperous and solid stone.
これで秦国は ますます繁栄
盤石の礎が築かれますぞ
この呂不韋 相国として―
As Prime Minister, I, Lü Buwei could have no greater joy.
これほど うれしいことは
ありませぬ
Oh, I know.
おお そうだ
Three days from now, how about we hold a national celebratory banquet?
本日より３日間 国を挙げて
祝いの宴(うたげ)をしたら どうかのぅ？
What do you think, Right Chancellor, Left Chancellor?
右丞相 左丞相
It sounds like an apt idea.
よきお考えかと…
（昌文君）わしにも異存はない
I have no objections.
Your majesty, these two have given their consent.
（呂不韋）大王さま
２人にも承諾をいただきましたぞ
I appreciate your thoughtfulness, Prime Minister.
心遣い感謝するぞ 相国
My king.
大王さま…
My lord, the winds are blowing in our favor...
殿 風は我らに吹いてきましたな
うむ… 王宮の勢力は
かろうじて拮抗(きっこう)を保っている
Yes.
The struggle for supremacy in the royal palace is just barely retaining.
Even Lü Buwei won't be able to make any outstanding moves for some time.
呂不韋も しばらくは
目立った動きは できないだろう
So why don't we take this opportunity to enjoy ourselves to our hearts' content?
だから今は この喜びに
存分 酔いしれようではないか
Yes, sir!
First, I've spoken some words of celebration, but...
（呂不韋）まずは
祝いの言葉を述べさせてもらったが
your future will not be a solid stone, king...
あなたの未来が
盤石とは いきませんぞ 大王
Lü Buwei... You are nothing more than an insect that's infested this country.
呂不韋
貴様は たかだか１国に巣くう虫
What I seek is the uniting of China.
俺が目指すのは中華の統一
Therefore, I must mercilessly eliminate all those that block my path.
だから 俺の道に立ちふさがる者は
容赦なく排除する
Prepare yourself, Lü Buwei!
覚悟しろ 呂不韋
What?! Zheng is having a kid?!
（太后）なに？ 政にガキが？
ハッ！ これは笑えるねえ
Now that's a laugh.
（趙高(ちょうこく)）はぁ？
（太后）だって そうじゃないか
You know.
He can barely even remember his own father's face...
ろくすっぽ
父親の顔も知らないくせにさ
フッ… あれが父親とはね
That's what fathers are like.
Xin
Oh yes.
（蒙恬）そうそう 知ってるか？ 信
（信）えっ？
Did you hear, Xin?
My teacher has been appointed as Right Chancellor and Changwenjun has been appointed Left Chancellor.
先生が右丞相に
昌文君が左丞相になられた
I had heard lots of rumors that Li Si was going to take the seat of Left Chancellor, but...
下馬評では 李斯の左丞相就任の
ウワサが高かったんだけど
昌文君の陣営が押し切ったようだ
But it seems that the Changwenjun camp prevailed.
（信）
昌文君のおっさんが左丞相に？
Old man Changwenjun became Left Chancellor?
Did you just call the Left Chancellor "old man"?
お前
左丞相を おっさん呼ばわりか？
Is that right? So Zheng and Lü Buwei are finally in all-out war, eh?
そうか　いよいよ 政が
呂不韋と全面戦争ってわけか！
大王と相国まで…
Even the king and the Prime Minister...?
But man, I can't wait to tell Diao about all this.
しっかし
今の話 貂(てん)にも教えてやらないとな
She'll flip her lid!
あいつ 驚くぞ ハハハハッ！
（蒙恬）ハァ…
So, is that all ya wanted to say?
だがよ
それが言いたかっただけか？
（蒙恬）まさか！
Not even close.
The main topic is on top of the Eastern wall, here.
本題は この東壁の上だ
（信）ふ～ん…
（信）ハッ… 王賁(おうほん)！
Wang Ben!
Why's he here?
なんで ここに？
（蒙恬）俺が呼んだんだよ
I called him.
That's right.
（王賁）そうだ
I heard you ran into Li Mu on the way here.
（蒙恬）ここに来る途中
李牧(りぼく)と遭遇したそうじゃないか
Yeah.
Want to tell us about it?
聞かせてくれるか？
That was 5 days before we got here.
あれは
ここに着く５日ほど前のことだ
It was at a place where the national borders of Wei, Zhao, Han, and Chu intersect.
場所は魏 趙 韓(かん) 楚(そ)の国境が
複雑に入り組んでる地点
We'd heard that an enemy was discovered and we hid on top of a cliff.
敵発見の報告に―
俺たちは崖の上に潜んで
その様子をうかがっていた
And when we went to see what was going on...
The carriage stopped!
（信）馬車が止まった！
Well, not like I'll know who he is by sight, though...
まあ 姿を見せたところで
どこの誰だって話だけどな…
あっ 李牧！
Li Mu!
Kaine!
（貂）カイネ！
（石(せき)）隊長 バレるぞ
Captain, we'll be seen.
We were really interested to find out what was goin' on, so Diao and I followed him.
（信）どうも気になったから
俺と貂は ヤツのあとを追ったんだ
A tent?! In this dense forest?!
天幕！ こんな密林の中に…
You little sneak!
（カイネ）曲者(くせもの)が！
（信）しまっ…
ハッ… お… お前は…
Y-You're...
ンンッ… よう！
Hey...
Why are you here?!
（カイネ）
なんで お前が ここにいる？
The Feixin Unit's Xin?
飛信隊 信？
Honestly, you really are a troublesome person, aren't you?
（李牧）
まったく あなたという人は…
本当に困った人ですね 飛信隊の信
Feixin Unit Xin.
And He Liao Diao.
それに 河了貂(かりょうてん)
It's been a while, Li Mu.
久しぶりだな 李牧
Yes. You look quite different.
そうですね　見違えましたよ
What're you doing sneaking around a place like this?
（信）こんな所でコソコソと
また何か悪だくみか？ 李牧
Concocting another scheme, Li Mu?
And I'll bet there's somebody inside that tent.
それに天幕の中に誰かいるようだが
一体 どこの どいつなんだ？
Who the hell is it?!
That is none of your business.
あなたには関係ありませんよ
Go!
（趙兵１）行け！
（信）ああ？
（趙兵２）黙って歩け！
（信）いってえな この野郎！
Shut up and walk!
That hurts, dammit!
What the hell?! Don't poke me with that!
なんだよ！
つつくんじゃねえよ！ 痛えな
李牧 信を殺す気か！
Li Mu!
Are planning on killing Xin?!
さて どうしましょうかね？
Hm, what shall we do?
Hey, are you okay with this?
（信）おい いいのか？
護衛を帰しちまって
Your guard is leaving.
Alliances are quite convenient things, aren't they?
（李牧）まったく
便利なものですね 同盟とは
Even if you're in front of an enemy you should cut down,
本来ならば
斬るべき相手を前にしても―
because of the Qin-Zhao alliance, you cannot lay a hand on me.
秦趙同盟があるせいで
あなたは 私に手出しができない
But to be honest, the goal of the alliance is not to keep one's hands off of their opponent.
しかし 同盟とは―
実は 相手に手を出させないことが
目的ではありません
What is important is what is gained and what is done once the alliance has ended.
重要なのは 同盟の先に
何を得るか 何をするかです
In that case, it's us that gained from the alliance.
だったら
同盟で得したのは 俺らだったな
The State of Qin gained a hugely important location called Shanyang.
秦国は 山陽(さんよう)っつう
でっけえ軍事拠点を手に入れたが
But the State of Zhao didn't gain any major areas in its war against the State of Yan.
趙国は 燕国(えんこく)との戦いで
大した土地は取ってねえ
（李牧）フッ… 戦いで得るものが
土地だけだと思っているうちは―
If you think that the only thing one can gain in a war is land...
then you'll never defeat me for your whole life long.
一生 あなたは 私に勝てませんよ
なっ… どういう意味だ？ 李牧！
What do you mean?!
You are planning something, aren't you, Li Mu?!
やっぱり
何か たくらんでやがるのか！
Now I can't just answer that honestly, now, can I?
（李牧）そう聞かれて
素直に答えるわけないですよねえ
But do you want to know?
でも 知りたいですか？
Quit screwing around with me, you bastard!
おちょくんな てめえ！
（李牧）では…
Well then...
how about a little one-on-one fight?
一騎打ちでも やってみますか？
If you beat me, I'll be fine with telling you all about my scheme.
あなたが勝ったら 私の悪だくみを
教えてあげてもいいですよ
Wh-What?!
な… なんだと！
Are you sure about this, Kaine?
（貂）いいのか？ カイネ
勝手に来ちゃって
They went off on their own like that.
Yes. There's no use worrying.
（カイネ）ああ
どうも気になって しかたない
（貂）
ハッ… まさか李牧は本当に信を…
Li Mu isn't really going to kill Xin, is he?!
Don't be an idiot.
（カイネ）
バカ！ 李牧さまは趙国の宰相だぞ
Lord Li Mu is the Prime Minister of the State of Zhao.
そんなこと するわけないだろう
He wouldn't do something like that.
The one I'm worried about is the one with the slanted eyes.
心配なのは つり目のほうだ
（貂）信だよ
It's Xin.
If he lays a hand on Lord Li Mu, he'll...
李牧さまに手を出したら あいつ…
Li Mu, I don't know why you're doing this shit,
李牧 お前が なんで―
こんな ふざけたマネしてくんのか
知んねえが
but when I fight, I fight with the intent to kill my opponent!
俺は やるからには マジで
相手をぶっ殺すつもりでいくぞ！
フッ… もし見事に殺せたら―
Of course, if you are able to kill me
私の悪だくみ そのものを
つぶすことができますよ
you'll be crushing my scheme itself.
Lord Li Mu!
（カイネ）李牧さま！
（信･李牧）ハッ…
There's an interference.
ジャマが入ったぞ
Do you have any questions?
何か問題でも？
Fine then!
（信）上等だ！
Lord Li Mu!
李牧さま！
（貂）信！ まさか本気で…
Xin!
Are you seriously going to fight all-out?!
This guy...
（信）こいつ…
ウワッ…
ええっ？ 信が吹き飛ばされた
Xin got pushed back?!
軍師の李牧に なんで…
（カイネ）バカ！
Li Mu is a strategist. How...?
You idiot.
What's made you think that Lord Li Mu is just a strategist?!
李牧さまが
ただの軍師と思ってるのは―
お前らの勝手な認識だ
Lord Li Mu was originally...
李牧さまは もともと…
What's with those muscles...?
何だ？ あの筋肉
All those scars...
いや あの多くの古傷は…
ヘヘッ… 思ってたとおりだぜ
Just as I thought.
I got that impression when I first saw you in Xiangyang.
咸陽で初めて お前を見たときに
そんな気がした
That you were definitely the sorta military commander that had tons of experience.
絶対 こいつは
場数を踏んだ武将のたぐいだってな
A gangly guy who only knew how to plan things
ただ 策だけの ひょろい男が―
あの王騎(おうき)将軍を
討てるわけもねえしな
could never defeat General Wang Qi.
お前は やっぱり知略と武勇を
兼ね備えたバケモノだ！
Like I thought, you're a monster equipped with both ingenuity and valor!
Did you perhaps accept my challenge in order to confirm that?
（李牧）ひょっとして それを
知るために 一騎打ちに乗ったと？
'A course!
（信）当たり前だ！
こんな所で お前を殺せるか！
Like hell I'd kill you at a place like this.
You're a wall I have to overcome head-on!
お前は 俺が正面から
越えなきゃなんねえ壁だからな！
フッ…
あなたも成長しているのですね
So you're growing as well, are you?
It seems your victory over Lun Hu was not just a fluke.
あの輪虎(りんこ)を討ったというのも
伊達(だて)ではなさそうです
（信）フン！ そうかよ
Is that right...?
Then what happened?
それから どうなった？
I'm embarassed to admit, but Diao and I were released in front of Li Mu's army.
（信）みっともねえ話だが
李牧軍の前で
俺と貂は解放されたよ
（蒙恬）そうか
しかし 気になるな 李牧の動き
I see. But what bothers me is Li Mu's movements.
What do you think, Wang Ben?
王賁は どう思う？
It must be a secret conference for a new alliance.
新たな同盟の密議だろう
I thought so...
やっぱり そうか…
Diao said that, too.
それは貂も言ってた
Li Mu.
（貂）李牧 趙国宰相自らが―
If the Prime Minister of the State of Zhao came out to a place like this and met with someone secretly,
こんな所で ひそかに
誰かと会っていたということは―
then it's not odd to assume that the one you're meeting is also the Prime Minister of someplace.
相手も
どこかの宰相と考えるのが普通だ
そして 秦国にとって最悪なのは
それが楚の宰相で
For the State of Qin, the worst possibility would be the Prime Minister of Chu
and that your secret meeting was about forming a Chu-Zhao alliance.
密会内容が
楚趙同盟に関するものだった場合だ
フッ… 最悪を想定するのは
軍師として正しいですよ 河了貂
Hypothesizing the worst-case scenario is the proper thing to do as a strategist, He Liao Diao.
さすがは飛信隊の頭脳を
担うだけのことはあります
I can see how you are able to carry the role of being the brains of the Feixin Unit.
Th-Then there is an alliance?!
じゃ… じゃ 同盟が…
I said this to Xin as well. What is important...
信にも言いましたが
重要なのは―
is not the alliance itself, but the "goal" and the "results" of it.
同盟自体ではなく
その目的と結果です
そして 結果は
また次の目的へと つながっていく
And those results link to the next goal.
W-What the hell are you...
なっ… 一体 どういう…
（李牧）
私が この場で与えられる警告は
The warning I can give here
is that even you two whom have built up quite a military career
戦歴を
重ねてきてる あなたたちでも―
実際のところ―
do not really understand the horror of war.
戦争の本当の恐ろしさは
分かっていないということです
Looking down on us, eh?
（信）ナメやがって…
面白(おもしれ)えじゃねえか 李牧
Interesting, Li Mu.
No matter what sorta plan you launch on the State of Qin,
お前が秦国に
どんな策を仕掛けてこようが―
俺は正面から
ぶっ飛ばしてやっかんな！
I'll crush it head on!
I wish you luck.
ご武運を
A Chu-Zhao Alliance?
（王賁）楚趙同盟か…
Just hearing it makes me shudder.
聞くだけでも ゾッとするね
If such a thing did happen, even the State of Qin would have no...
もし そんなものがあるとしたら
秦国にしても 何らかの手を…
Even if we, say, allied with Wei...
例えば 魏国と組むとか…
（信）楚趙同盟じゃねえ
It's not a Chu-Zhao Alliance!
Something was odd about Li Mu back then.
あのときの李牧は なんか変だった
You can be sure that he's trying to do something... much more incredible.
ヤツは もっと とんでもねえことを
やろうとしてるに違(ちげ)えねえ
With Wang Qi's death and General Meng Ao being injured and effectively retiring after that last war,
（王賁）王騎の死…
先の戦で負傷し
事実上 引退した蒙驁(もうごう)将軍
our military power has undeniably decreased. And now an even larger war is going to occur?
軍事力の低下が否めない中
更に大きな戦が起こるということか
There's going to be a storm across all of China...
中華全土に嵐が来るな
Yeah, and you can bet that that man is going to be in the center of it!
（信）ああ　そして
その中心にいるのは絶対 あの男だ
Li Mu...
李牧…
But that's not bad.
（信）だが それも悪くねえ
どの道 列国を―
One way or another, we're going to crush every one of the other states.
ぶっ飛ばして回ることに
なるんだからな
A big war is better than anything we could ever ask for.
大きな戦があるなら願ったりだ！
It'll never happen if you don't get going!
モタモタしてっと終わらねえ
（蒙恬･王賁）うん
I'm going to blow away the legends myself!
俺が この手で
伝説を塗り替えるんだからな！
フッ… “中華統一”
廉頗(れんぱ)が そう言っていたな
Uniting China.
Lian Po said that, didn't he?
Uniting China...
中華統一… 正に伝説になる偉業だ
Truly a deed that would go down in legends.
Zheng, our king, said this.
政が…
俺たちの王さまが言ってたぜ
What does uniting China mean?
中華を統一することが
どういうことなのか
It means putting an end to the last 500 years of war.
（信）500年続いた戦乱の世に
終止符を打つってことだ
So no matter what kind of storm arrives, we'll overcome it!
だから どんな嵐がやって来ようが
乗り切ってみせるぜ
And that is the path to becoming the greatest general under the heavens!
そして それが…
天下の大将軍への道だ！
Isn't that right... Zheng?
そうだろう？
政！
Feixin Unit, let's go!
（信）
飛信隊 いくぞー！
ヤーッ！ 道を開けろ！
Open a path!
I'm Xin of the Feixin Unit!
俺が飛信隊の信だー！
End